<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-12-06T12:25:19-08:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">j4qfrost.github.io</title><entry><title type="html">Too Many Goddamn Laws!</title><link href="/2020/12/06/Too-Many-Goddamn-Laws/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Too Many Goddamn Laws!" /><published>2020-12-06T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-12-06T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>/2020/12/06/Too-Many-Goddamn-Laws</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/12/06/Too-Many-Goddamn-Laws/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;preface&quot;&gt;Preface&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;        I have been reading an enlightening book titled &lt;em&gt;You Have the Right to Remain Innocent&lt;/em&gt; by James Duane, which inspired an idea. The federal criminal code in America is perversely gargantuan and is a clear demonstration of government overreach and hubris. The title of a book by civil liberties lawyer, Harvey Silvergate, &lt;em&gt;Three Felonies a Day&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;, refers to the estimate that the average American commits at least three felonies daily without even realizing it. Federal conservation laws prohibit possession of a “short lobster,” yes a lobster that is too small.&lt;a href=&quot;#2&quot;&gt;[Duane 18]&lt;/a&gt; America clearly has an overcriminalization problem. Day to day, this probably isn’t an issue; what police officer is going to go around measuring your lobsters and arresting you for inadequate lobster size? It’s absurd, but the question still stands. As long as a law is on the books, a police state could use that law to justify an arrest whether the arrest was a morally sound decision or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;        My peers and I have been so incredibly fortunate to be raised in an environment where despite these insane laws, individual freedoms have generally been upheld, but I have been to countries where those liberties are only reserved for the class of people wealthy enough to pay for them. This issue is also present in America though to expound on that here would lead to a long, dicey tangent, which I don’t shy from, but we have other things to discuss here. The key issues that I want to solve are problems with classism which are often conflated with problems pertaining to racism, though the two often intermingle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;proposal&quot;&gt;Proposal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;        As the title states, we have too many goddamn laws. If you want to stay out of trouble, it’s not enough to follow an internal moral code anymore. I want to create tools in order to tear down some of these horrendous laws and to help revitalize them in order to maintain a legal system that both pass judgement with clear intentions and is flexible to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;        Normally, you would have to send a reasonably smart child to a knowledge factory for the better part of a decade, spend a small fortune, and then hope that the kid turns out to be a half decent lawyer. Then, maybe that lawyer could spend time reading our vast criminal code and figure out where the absurdities lie. That lawyer would then have to educate the public and run for office to even have the power to come close to effecting change. Turns out legislatures have an incentive to continual pump out haphazard legal documents, because “that’s their job” and that kid turned lawyer turned politician has to review new legislation on top of the flawed ones he discovered before. How old is that bright-eyed kid now? Has he grown tired and jaded by the system or corrupt and hopeless? This isn’t tenable. We need to solve this problem before the kid becomes part of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;        Machines are much more suited for the job of collating data in short periods of time than humans. The only issue is proper classification of the meaning of that data. Until more recently, a computer would not have been able to &lt;em&gt;understand&lt;/em&gt; human speech let alone generate meaningful dialogue. Nowadays, with enough processing power and some trickery, object classification and semantic analysis on speech patterns is becoming quite viable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;        So my proposal: build a platform that will analyze legal documents and criminal code and classify semantic patterns with the intention of evaluating contradictions or broad/vague language. If we can spot these problems, we can educate the populace and empower legislature to overturn legal code that is irrelevant and cumbersome to society or work to redraft them. The models generated for solving this problem can also be used to help draft more secure laws in the future, so we can cut down on the necessity of legislative government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;afterthoughts&quot;&gt;Afterthoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;        I am not so naive as to think that this idea will be immediately accepted. There are people who are technophobic, and any time you talk about reducing the labor force, people go into a frenzy. Technology has allowed the human race to reclaim so much more time in the form of leisure so that we have the choice to work or play. There’s a possiblity that this is downright impossible, but it’s worth a shot, and I think harder problems have been solved before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;
Silvergate, Harvey A. (2011).
Three Felonies A Day: How the Feds Target the Innocent
Encounter Books (June 7, 2011)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;
Duane, James, (2016).
You Have the Right to Remain Innocent
Little A, New York (2016)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>frosty</name></author><category term="politics" /><category term="law" /><summary type="html">Preface         I have been reading an enlightening book titled You Have the Right to Remain Innocent by James Duane, which inspired an idea. The federal criminal code in America is perversely gargantuan and is a clear demonstration of government overreach and hubris. The title of a book by civil liberties lawyer, Harvey Silvergate, Three Felonies a Day[1], refers to the estimate that the average American commits at least three felonies daily without even realizing it. Federal conservation laws prohibit possession of a “short lobster,” yes a lobster that is too small.[Duane 18] America clearly has an overcriminalization problem. Day to day, this probably isn’t an issue; what police officer is going to go around measuring your lobsters and arresting you for inadequate lobster size? It’s absurd, but the question still stands. As long as a law is on the books, a police state could use that law to justify an arrest whether the arrest was a morally sound decision or not.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Compromise, Control, Pandemic</title><link href="/2020/03/20/Compromise-Control-Pandemic/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Compromise, Control, Pandemic" /><published>2020-03-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-03-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/2020/03/20/Compromise-Control-Pandemic</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/03/20/Compromise-Control-Pandemic/">&lt;p&gt;        What’s your price? People would often quote some absurdly large number, without truly understanding how inconsequential money is to the question posed. When a person looks to buy your soul, he will do so in installments, and he will tell you there are no refunds. This global pandemic is something we’re in together, but let’s not forget how we got here in the first place. Americans chose to compromise on our stated principles, looking to enrich ourselves by investing in an authoritarian government. Capitalism is a tool that can work wonders for people who know how to use it properly and with proper wisdom, but it is absolutely not in one’s best interest to sell weapons to someone who is deeply unprincipled. There was a hope by the public that opening up China to capitalism would liberalize its government. We intended to buy into the system and strongarm the Chinese government into changing their authoritarian practices. Where was the effort made to address the human rights abuses? Instead of making public threats to pull out of China, businesses continued to apologize for China’s savagry, keeping their heads down. Businesses quietly made excuses saying that if they don’t participate in the Chinese market, then their competition will do so anyway. Companies justify their participation with the conceit that they are morally superior to other companies, and so would not be vulnerable to the temptations put forth by the Chinese Communist Party. Each unholy compromise twists the soul; every excuse taxes the mind. Mistakes are forgivable, but today we are taught that any mistake is irredeemable, so rather than acknowledging our own wrongdoings we divert the attention to bigger fish. We have been conditioned through educational institutions and social media to avoid mistakes and to not get caught rather than learn and become better people. In a healthy compromise you need accountability. We didn’t hold China accountable for their atrocities and found ourselves controlled by their interests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;        Among the informed participants of the Chinese economy there are two classes of people: the one who is fully committed to the evils perpetrated by the Chinese government and the one who can’t face the reality of the evil they’ve been a party to. It is a moot point to discuss the former. The latter is in denial about their situation, being placed in a position where there appears to be no way out. I have witnessed Chinese students in America vehemently defend China and deny claims against the Party’s blatant human rights violations: imprisonment and “reeducation” of Muslims, harvesting the organs of Falun Gong practitioners, and cracking down on Hong Kong’s civil liberties, to name a few recent examples. The defense for these students is that their families are held hostage by the Party, but that’s precisely why one should revolt. Why choose to live a pitiful life of false security when you can take a chance at freedom? No, there is no choice between safety and freedom. How long until the Party asks for your mind and your body in service to a “greater good”? Those families that the Party keeps as hostages, they’re dead unless the Party is ended. Both classes live in the delusion that they won’t be affected by the evils of the Party whether by the safety of keeping their heads down or being too important to be vulnerable to the same consequences, but well, coronavirus is a thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;        People tend to be complacent about problems until those problems are at their doorstep. Well, the China virus is knocking at their door, the door of every American family and hell the door of basically all the world’s families, China included. It’s not the literal coronavirus that people should have been vigilant for; it’s the panic and the people who spread the panic. COVID-19 is just a medium, a vessel for the incompetence of the Party and bureaucrats everywhere; let’s not single out China. Who is responsible for the mass panic? Doctors in Wuhan had reported the existence of the virus for months, and in those months the Party silenced doctors with the intention of curbing panic. Unsurprisingly, the virus spread and so did the panic. Rather than solving the underlying problem and acknowledging their own mistakes, China decided to reject America’s offer to help and instead impose draconian measures on its citizens in order to curb the spread. Now rather than taking ownership of the problem, the Party decides to pin the virus on America. Okay bro, you keep welding the doors of your citizens shut and leaving them for dead. I’m sure your credibility hasn’t completely tanked yet. I mean you have American news whores shilling out lies to the world. Even while the people of China are struggling to survive, the Chinese Communist Party is desparately trying to spin the narrative in order to retain their power. The handling of the coronavirus isn’t the first example of this kind of behavior, it’s simply the first one that has hit Americans and the rest of the developed world in a very real way. For a long list of Pooh and the rest of the Party’s misadventures, I recommend China Uncensored on Youtube. There has never been a more opportune time to reconsider our institutions and tear them down if we find this kind of behavior permeating them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;        I’ve been mulling over the phrase “if you see something, say something” a lot. In the context that it is often conveyed, this adage is often a mantra for good, but in practice, I have more often seen the principle behind the phrase ignored or misused. Describing the latter case, there are times when flaws are pointed out in an ineffectual manner, whether by timing, focus, or attitude. One should always consider the maxim “there’s a time and place for everything” but should never use it as an excuse for avoiding an issue altogether. Even with ill-timed or ill-mannered acknowledgement of a problem, there is still acknowledgement of the problem. I understand the necessity for prioritizing issues with the best possible knowledge, and I understand that people are truly ignorant of the problem at times, but it is the height of hubris to believe that you are ever safe from tyranny. Never take for granted the comforts that our predecessors died to achieve. It is not our responsiblity to uplift others from poverty, it should be our pleasure to. We should not profit off the misery of others, while turning a blind eye to their inherent flaws. We should never have done business with a system that is as ethically flawed as China without leveraging that influence to impose our values on them. How do I know the American value system is better than China’s? Well say what you want about America, but… no seriously, it’s a free country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#partysover&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>frosty</name></author><category term="politics" /><summary type="html">        What’s your price? People would often quote some absurdly large number, without truly understanding how inconsequential money is to the question posed. When a person looks to buy your soul, he will do so in installments, and he will tell you there are no refunds. This global pandemic is something we’re in together, but let’s not forget how we got here in the first place. Americans chose to compromise on our stated principles, looking to enrich ourselves by investing in an authoritarian government. Capitalism is a tool that can work wonders for people who know how to use it properly and with proper wisdom, but it is absolutely not in one’s best interest to sell weapons to someone who is deeply unprincipled. There was a hope by the public that opening up China to capitalism would liberalize its government. We intended to buy into the system and strongarm the Chinese government into changing their authoritarian practices. Where was the effort made to address the human rights abuses? Instead of making public threats to pull out of China, businesses continued to apologize for China’s savagry, keeping their heads down. Businesses quietly made excuses saying that if they don’t participate in the Chinese market, then their competition will do so anyway. Companies justify their participation with the conceit that they are morally superior to other companies, and so would not be vulnerable to the temptations put forth by the Chinese Communist Party. Each unholy compromise twists the soul; every excuse taxes the mind. Mistakes are forgivable, but today we are taught that any mistake is irredeemable, so rather than acknowledging our own wrongdoings we divert the attention to bigger fish. We have been conditioned through educational institutions and social media to avoid mistakes and to not get caught rather than learn and become better people. In a healthy compromise you need accountability. We didn’t hold China accountable for their atrocities and found ourselves controlled by their interests.</summary></entry></feed>